Finding Aid for the Jan Williams Collection of Annotated Scores, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Instruments, no. 3 Instruments III / Morton Feldman. c1977., 1 ms. score (14 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 4, Item 53)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). For flute (alto flute, piccolo), oboe (English horn), and percussion. Caption title. "Copyright Universal EDT 1977"--Bottom of leaf 1. At end of score: July 15, '77. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 The King of Denmark: percussion / Morton Feldman New York, N.Y.: C.F. Peters, c1965., 3 leaves of music; 28 cm. (Box 4, Item 54)
  For solo percussionist. Cover title. At end of score: Aug. 1964. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Includes additional 9 leaves: 1 heavily marked photocopy of score; 1 photocopy of leaf 1 of score; 5 leaves containing diagrams of instrument set-up and lists of instruments required.
- Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Why patterns? / M. Feldman. [1978], 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 42 cm. (Box 4, Item 55)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). For flute (doubling alto & bass flute), piano and glockenspiel. Caption title. At end of score: April, 1978. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Markings include some changes to score.
- Festinger, Richard A serenade for six: for flute, clarinet/bass clarinet, violin, cello, percussion, and piano / Richard Festinger. c1993., 1 part (9 p.); 36 cm. (Box 4, Item 56)
  Computer printout of percussion part. Dedicated to the New York New Music Ensemble. Performance instructions on verso of title page. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Finnissy, Michael Hinomi: for solo percussionist / Michael Finnissy. [1979], 7 p. of ms. music; 28 x 41 cm. (Box 4, Item 57)
  Reproduced from holograph. Composer's instructions, in English, prelim. p. Cover title. At end of score: December 1979. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Ford, Andrew Boatsong / Andrew Ford. 1982], 1 ms. score (8 p.); 37 cm. (Box 4, Item 58)
  Reproduced from holograph. For bass clarinet or alto saxophone, and marimba or vibraphone. "Commissioned by Henri Bok and Evert Le Mair, the Duo Contemporain, and is dedicated to them." On verso: Andrew Ford Menston, Yorkshire 1982. At end: "Andrew Ford, March-August 1982, Isle of Skye- Sutton Valence." Duration: ca. 10:00. Inscription on title page. from the composer to percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Concertos, percussion, orchestra Concerto for solo percussion and large or small orchestra: 1973-74 / Lukas Foss. [1974], 1 ms. score (14, [4] p.); 28 x 37 cm. (Box 4, Item 59)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Chance composition. Duration: 29:00 (large orchestra version); 29:00 or 47:00 (small orchestra version). "Commissioned by the Ford Foundation for Jan Williams"--2nd. title page. Stamp on title page.: Editions Salabert Rental Library. List of instruments and their stage positions attached to front cover. Score marked #2.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Concertos, percussion, orchestra Concerto for solo percussion and large or small orchestra / Lukas Foss New York: Editions Salabert, c1975., 1 score (29 p.); 26 x 36 cm. + 2 parts; 33-36 cm. (Box 4, Item 60)
  Chance composition. Composer's performance instructions on p. 3-5. Duration: 30:00 (short version); 46:00 (long version). "Commissioned by the Ford Foundation for Jan Williams"--At head of title. Stamp on title page.: Editions Salabert Rental Library. Violin and Percussion parts included, with additional pages. Score marked P#4. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Additional materials inserted: 2 photocopies of typescript program notes; equipment list and set-up diagram (4 leaves); enlarged portions of score (ms.) for placement on different percussion stands (6 leaves); 4 more leaves of miscellaneous notes.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Concertos, percussion, orchestra Concerto for solo percussion and large or small orchestra: 1973-74 / Lukas Foss. [1974], 1 ms. score (14, [4] leaves); 28 x 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 61)
  Holograph (Photocopy). Chance composition. Duration: 29:00 (large orchestra version); 29:00 or 47:00 (small orchestra version). "Commissioned by the Ford Foundation for Jan Williams"--2nd. title page. Stamp on title page.: Editions Salabert. Disbound loose leaves. Heavily marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Concertos, percussion, orchestra Concerto for solo percussion and large or small orchestra: 1973-74 / Lukas Foss. [1974], 1 ms. score (14, [4] leaves); 26 x 36 cm. (Box 4, Item 62)
  Holograph (Photocopy). Chance composition. Duration: 29:00 (large orchestra version); 29:00 or 47:00 (small orchestra version). "Commissioned by the Ford Foundation for Jan Williams"--2nd. title page. Loose leaves. "Revised April 1975 after performances April 10, 11 + 13 with NJ Symphony (Jesse Levine)." Includes 5 additional leaves, marked "Large version", of enlarged ms. for placement on percussion stands. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Curriculum vitae with time-bomb: for percussion solo and taped or live accordeon [sic]: 1980 / Lukas Foss. 1980., 1 ms. score (9 leaves); 36 x 46 cm. (Box 4, Item 63)
  Printed Pembroke Music score (1978) of Curriculum vitae, for solo accordion, with ms. addition of percussion part. "For Jan Williams." Performance instructions on title page. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Additional materials inserted: 1 extra photocopy of score (22 x 36 cm.) with additional markings, and list of percussion instruments required.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Map / Lukas Foss. 1977., [14] leaves; 28 cm. (Box 5, Item 64)
  Typescript, with pencil annotations by the composer. For four performers and electronic tapes.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Ni bruit ni vitesse: for piano keys (pianist) and piano strings (percussionist) / Lukas Foss. 1971., 1 ms. score (5 leaves); 34 x 49 cm. (Box 5, Item 65)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For 2 pianos and 2 percussionists (playing on the piano strings) or 1 piano, 1 percussionist, and tape; in part, aleatoric. Duration: 13:00. Performance instructions on title page. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Ni bruit ni vitesse: for piano keys (pianist) and piano strings (percussionist) / Lukas Foss. 1971., 1 ms. score (10 leaves); 34 x 49 cm. (Box 5, Item 66)
  Holograph (Photocopy). "Final draft." For 2 pianos and 2 percussionists (playing on the piano strings) or 1 piano, 1 percussionist, and tape; in part, aleatoric. Duration: 13:30. Performance instructions on title page. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 [Paradigm / Lukas Foss]. [1968?], 1 ms. score ([8] leaves); 32 x 49 cm. (Box 5, Item 67)
  Title page lacking. Holograph (Ozalid copy). For percussionist/conductor, electric guitar (or sitar) and three other unspecified instruments capable of sustaining a sound. Narration performed by the instrumentalists; also requires tape recorder. Text in English with some German and French translations. Duration: ca. 17:30. Includes performance instructions. Leaves numbered: 1A, 2A, 2B, 2C, 3, 4A, 4B, 4C. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Paradigm: for percussionist/conductor, electric guitar (or sitar) and three other instruments capable of sustaining a sound / Lukas Foss. 1968., 1 folder ([39] leaves); 32 x 49 cm. (Box 5, Item 68)
  Holograph (Ozalid and photocopy). Folder containing scores (also used as parts) and additional materials (including pitch choices) compiled by the composer for performance of the work. Narration performed by the instrumentalists; also requires tape recorder. Text in English with some German and French translations. Duration: ca. 17:30. Includes performance instructions. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams and other performers. Four movements: I. Session -- II. Reading -- III. Recital -- IV. Lecture.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Paradigm: for percussionist/conductor (one man), electric guitar or electric sitar [and] three other instruments capable of sustaining a sound / Lukas Foss Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne; New York: C. Fischer, c1969., 4 scores (23 p. each); 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 69)
  Scores (with 1 additional photocopy) compiled by percussionist/conductor Jan Williams; used as parts and marked for performance. Narration performed by the instrumentalists; also requires tape recorder. Duration: about 18 min.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Solo observed / [Lukas Foss]. [1982?], 1 ms. part ([8] leaves); 28-38 cm. (Box 5, Item 70)
  Ms. (Photocopy). Caption title. "This work is an extended version of Solo, for piano, involving the addition of a coda consisting of vibraphone or marimba, violoncello or harp, and electronic organ or accordion reflecting on the pianist's solo which they "observe"--Lukas Foss: a bio-bibliography / Karen L. Perone. Score cut and pasted for use as a percussion part; last 3 leaves are mounted on cardboard backing. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird: a setting of Wallace Stevens' poem / Lukas Foss. 1978., 1 ms. score (17 leaves); 28 cm. (Box 5, Item 71)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For voice (soprano or mezzo-soprano, possibly tenor or high baritone), percussion (1 performer playing inside the piano on strings with tape covered triangle beaters, 2 cowbells, 2 bowls balancing on piano strings, and using a superball mallet, flexatron and Jew's harp), piano, and flute; with 2 tape recorders (optional). Includes performance instructions. Duration: ca. 13:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Fulkerson, James In quest of a silence / Jim Fulkerson. [1977], 3 parts; 42 cm. (Box 5, Item 72)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). For trombone, vibraphone, and piano. Caption title. Includes performance instructions. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Fuller, Ramon Conrad, 1930- Music for two channel tape and two percussionists / Ramon Fuller. [196-], 1 ms. score (24 p.); 40 cm. (Box 5, Item 73)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Marked for performance by Jan Williams as Percussion 2 part.
- Gaber, Harley, 1943- The silent zero: 1973 / Harley Gaber. 1973., 2 ms. scores (3 leaves each); 45 cm. (Box 5, Item 74)
  Caption title. Holograph (photocopy). For percussion (2 players). At end: New York City-New Paltz, N.Y., Dec. 1973. Marked as parts for performance.
- Gaber, Harley, 1943- Voce, no. 2 Voce II: female voice, alto flute, percussion / Gaber Cincinnati: Apogee, c1967., 2 scores (vii, 19 p.); 44 cm. (Box 5, Item 75)
  Includes biographical note and performance instructions in English. Percussion (1 player): vibraphone, xylophone, wind chimes. Both scores marked for performance. Japanese words (romanized) also printed as text on p. vii.
- García, Orlando Jacinto The German archer / by O. Garcia. 1985., 5 ms. scores (12 p. each); 44 cm. (Box 6, Item 76)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For flute/alto flute, clarinet, and percussion (2 players). "3/85." "Dedicated to Morton Feldman." Four of the scores used as instrumental parts. Marked for performance.
- García, Orlando Jacinto In deference to the king / by Orlando Jacinto Garcia. [1989], 1 ms. score (13 leaves); 44 cm. + 1 ms. part ([8] leaves); 36 cm. (Box 6, Item 77)
  Caption title. Holograph (Photocopy). For flute/piccolo, oboe/English horn, B-flat/Bass clarinet, percussion (1 player), piano, violin, and violoncello. "The king in the title refers to Morton Feldman's The king of Denmark."--leaf 13. Performance instructions at end of score. "OJ, 7/89, Miami, FL."--At end of score. Duration: 16:00. Percussion part included. Score marked for performance by Jan Williams. Includes additional photocopy of leaves 8-12 with percussion part highlighted.
- García, Orlando Jacinto Four individual migrations / by Orlando J. Garcia. [1986], 1 ms. score (6 leaves); 44 cm. (Box 6, Item 78)
  Holograph (photocopy). For clarinet, percussion (2 players), and piano. Revised version; originally composed as 3 individual migrations; for clarinet and percussion (1 player). At end of score: 8/86. Duration: ca. 18:00. Percussion II part marked for performance throughout the score.
- García, Orlando Jacinto Metallic images: for percussion and tape / by Orlando Jacinto Garcia. [1991], 1 ms. score (3 leaves); 33 cm. (Box 6, Item 79)
  Caption title. Holograph (Photocopy). For tape and percussionist playing vibraphone, glockenspiel, finger cymbals, 3 triangles. "For Jan Williams." Performance instructions at end. "OJ, 2/91, Miami, FL."--At end. Duration: ca. 21:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Gibson, David, 1943- Lillian Brook / David Gibson. [1977], 1 ms. score (28 leaves); 28 x 44 cm. (Box 6, Item 80)
  Cover title. Reproduced from ms. For vibraphone. "For my friend Jan Williams." "The durations of each line must remain flexable [sic] and the pages need not follow in any particular order. Any amount of the work may be performed." Includes performance instructions, typescript, 1 leaf and ms., 1 leaf. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Gibson, David, 1943- Shadows: for 3 percussionists / by David Gibson. [197-], 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 36 x 51 cm. (Box 6, Item 81)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). "For Jan Williams." Marked for performance in all parts.
- Gibson, David, 1943- Shadows: for 3 percussionists / by David Gibson. [197-], 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 36 x 51 cm. (Box 6, Item 82)
- Gibson, David, 1943- Shadows: for 3 percussionists / by David Gibson. [197-], 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 36 x 51 cm. (Box 6, Item 83)
- Globokar, Vinko, 1934- Correspondences: für vier Solisten = for four soloists = pour quatre solistes / Vinko Globokar Frankfurt; New York: H. Litolff's Verlag: C.F. Peters, c1971., 1 score (6 leaves); 45 cm. (Box 7, Item 84)
  "Edition Peters, Nr. 8111." For 4 performers; one each of string, woodwind and brass instruments, or chordal instruments, and percussionist. Reproduced from holograph. "Explanation of symbols" in German, English and French ([2] p.) laid in. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Globokar, Vinko, 1934- Vibone: fantaisie pour trombone et vibraphone: 1963 / Vinko Globokar. 1963., 1 ms. score (9 p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Item 85)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Includes performance instructions in French. Duration: 6:30. Inscription on title page. from composer to Jan Williams.
- Grosskopf, Erhard Nexus: 1968 / Grosskopf. 1968., 1 ms. score (8 leaves); 34 x 46 cm. (Box 7, Item 86)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Title from margin, leaf 1. For flute, percussion, electronic tape, and optical elements (by Bernhard Damke). At end of score: Berlin, 6.9.1968. Duration: ca. 17:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003 [Ariadne / Lou Harrison]. [1987], 1 ms. score ([3] leaves); 28 x 44 cm. (Box 7, Item 87)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For flute and percussion. At end of leaf [2]: 30 March, 1987. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hassell, Jon, 1937- Music for vibraphones and tape (1965): for two vibraphones and 2-track magnetic tape / Jon Hassell [S.l.], 1965., 1 ms. score (18 p.); 31 x 46 cm. (Box 7, Item 88)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). At end: "Feb.-April 1965." Duration: ca. 11:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hassell, Jon, 1937- Music for vibraphones and tape (1965): for two vibraphones and 2-track magnetic tape / Jon Hassell [S.l.], 1965., 1 ms. score (18 p.); 31 x 46 cm. (Box 7, Item 89)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy, except for original holograph title page.). At end: "Feb.-April 1965." Duration: ca. 11:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman Alone, no. 1 Alone 1: for low instruments / [Roman Haubenstock-Ramati]. [between 1965 and 1980?], 2 scores ([1] leaf each); 30 x 40 cm. (Box 7, Item 90)
  Title from ms. leaf of instructions. Chance composition for low instruments. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams; includes 1 ms. leaf of instructions. Photocopy.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman Batterie: 1969 / Roman Haubenstock-Ramati Vienna: Ariadne, [1980?], 1 score ([1] leaf); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 7, Item 91)
  Title from caption beneath graphic notation. Chance composition. For percussion ensemble of unspecified size. Includes 3 enlarged photocopies. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Photocopy.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman Decisions: 1959-1961 / Haubenstock-Ramati. [1980?], 16 leaves of music; 22 x 30 cm. (Box 7, Item 92)
  Title from cover sheet. Chance composition for unspecified sound sources; graphic notation; lacks performance instructions. Two copies of score: one unmarked, the other marked and with page order arranged for performance. Photocopy.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman In memoriam Igor S. / Haubenstock-Ramati. [1980?], [2] leaves of music; 22 x 30 cm. (Box 7, Item 93)
  Title from cover sheet. Chance composition for unspecified sound sources; graphic notation. Consists of leaves 3 (1 copy) and 6 (4 copies) of the composer's work, Decisions, with 1 ms. leaf of instructions. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Photocopy.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman Kreise: for Sprechstimme and percussion / [Roman Haubenstock-Ramati]. [1980?], 1 leaf of music; 30 x 42 cm. (Box 7, Item 94)
  For speaking voice and percussion (unspecified). Caption title. Graphic notation; one area composed of newspaper clippings in English. Duration: ca. 10:00. "Notation as in "Decisions""--Verso, leaf [1]. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Photocopy.
- Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman Liaisons / Roman Haubenstock-Ramati London: Universal Edition, c1961., 3 scores (1 folded leaf each); 31-52 cm. (Box 7, Item 95)
  Cover title. In part graphic notation. Includes performance instructions by the composer. "'Liaisons' are written for vibraphone, or vibraphone coupled with marimbaphone. The work can also be executed 'a` 2' by two performers, or one performer and a previously prepared tape recording." Duration: 7:00-8:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Helweg, Kim, 1956- Behind the curtain: a poem for piano and percussion: 1988-89 / Kim Helweg. 1989., 1 ms. part (2 v.); 37 cm. (Box 7, Item 96-97)
  Caption title. Ms. (Photocopy). Both parts are for the percussionist, for different sections of the work. At end: March 1985. Photocopy of parts with performance markings.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms, no. 2. Version, no. 1 Algorithms II: score of version 1 / Lejaren Hiller, Ravi Kumra. 1972., 1 score (19 p.); 37 cm. (Box 7, Item 98)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For flute, clarinet, bassoon, trumpet, harp, percussion, violin, violoncello, double bass, and tape recorder. "SUNY/Buffalo, August 1972." Marked for performance by percussionist/conductor Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms, no. 2. Version, nos. 1-4 Algorithms II: score of version [1-4] / Lejaren Hiller [and] Ravi Kumra. 1972., 4 ms. scores (19 p. each); 28 cm. (Box 7, Item 99)
  Cover title. Holograph (Photocopy). For flute, clarinet, bassoon, trumpet, harp, percussion (1 player), violin, violoncello, double bass, and tape. "SUNY/Buffalo, August 1972"--Cover. Marked for performance by percussionist/conductor Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Apotheosis of archaeopterix An apotheosis of archaeopterix: for piccolo and berimbau: 1979 / Lejaren Hiller. 1979., 1 ms. score (13 leaves); 28 cm. (Box 7, Item 100)
  Holograph (Photocopy). At end of score: Buffalo, August, 1979. At head of title page.: 59 (Hiller's work list number assigned to this work). Pencil annotation at head of title page.: 1st draft. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Computer music, percussion, tape Computer music for percussion and tape / Lejaren Hiller and G. Allan O'Connor; arranged from Strophes I, II and IV of Computer cantata by Lejaren Hiller and Robert Baker Bryn Mawr, Penn.: T. Presser, [c1972], 8 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 101)
  For one percussion player with magnetic tape. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Persiflage: for flute, oboe and percussion / Lejaren Hiller. 1977., 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 44 cm. (Box 8, Item 102)
  Holograph (Photocopy). At end of score: 5/23/77. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Rituals Three rituals for two percussion, projections and lights: 1969 / Lejaren Hiller [S.l.]: L. Hiller, c1973., 1 score (viii, 75 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 103)
  Printed score and photocopies compiled and prepared for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Incomplete. Two covers: marked "Performance copy"; "Extra pages."
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Rituals Three rituals: for two percussion and lights (1969) / Lejaren Hiller [S.l., 1969], 1 ms. score (58 p.); 37 cm. (Box 8, Item 104)
  Holograph (Photocopy). Includes performance instructions. "Ureques, Puerto Rico, Dec. 27, 1969"--At end. Duration: ca. 27:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Husa, Karel, 1921- Concertos, percussion, band Concerto for percussion and wind ensemble New York: Associated Music Publishers, [c1973], 1 score (92 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 105)
  For 5 percussionists. Inscribed by the composer to Jan Williams. Duration: about 18 min.
- Husa, Karel, 1921- Dance sketches Three dance sketches: for percussion / Karel Husa New York: Associated Music Publishers, c1982., 1 score (38 p.); 30 cm. (Box 8, Item 106)
  For 4 or more performers. Inscribed by the composer to Williams.
- Ishii, Maki Sen-ten: für einen Schlagzeugspieler und elektronische Klänge / Maki Ishii Celle: Moeck, c1972., 1 score (16 p.); 16 x 22 cm. (Box 8, Item 107)
  For a percussionist and electronic sounds. Duration: ca. 13:00. Lacking title page. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Johnston, Ben In memory: (1975) / Ben Johnston; text after Walter Savage Landor. [1975], 1 ms. score (8 leaves) + 13 parts; 37 cm. +1 letter (28 cm.) (Box 8, Item 108)
  For soprano, percussion ensemble, strings, tape, slides, and optional scalatron (electronic microtonal keyboard instrument). Caption title. Words in English. "In Memory, Harry Partch 1975"--accompanying letter (1 ms. leaf) from the composer to Lejaren Hiller, Feb. 17, 1983. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Johnston, Ben Knocking piece: for piano interior (2 players) / Ben Johnston Davis, Calif.: Composer/Performer Edition, c1967., 1 score (leaves 85-90); 28 x 36 cm. (Box 9, Item 109)
  For 2 percussionists. Reprinted from Source. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Johnston, Ben Knocking piece / Ben Johnston. [1962], 2 ms. scores (4 leaves); 35 cm. (Box 9, Item 110)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Caption title. Derived from A sea dirge. For two percussionists to play on the inside of a grand piano. Includes performance instructions. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Jones, Daniel Sonatas, timpani Sonata: for three unaccompanied kettledrums (one player) / Daniel Jones London: Hinrichsen Edition Ltd., 1953., 1 score (11 p.); 34 cm. (Box 9, Item 111)
  Annotated for performance by Jan Williams. Duration: 10:00.
- Kagel, Mauricio 1898: für Kinderstimmen und Instrumente (1972/73) / Mauricio Kagel London: Universal Edition, 1973., 1 score (93 p.); 29 cm. (Box 9, Item 112)
  For 11-17 performers, including piano and percussion, and any other instruments, and 20-25 children, 10-13 years old, either live or recorded on tape. "Reproduktion des Autographs." Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams; also contains changes marked in red pencil by the composer (Ottawa, 1974). Includes 3 leaves (46 cm.) of pencil ms. performance notes.